Guide to the Research Institute for the Study of Man (RISM) Vertical Files RISM.VF.1
New York University Archives
- Grenada
  - Grenada: Politics and Government, Maurice Bishop (Box 11)
    - Maurice Bishop's Mother Accepts Invitation to Visit the United States of America; Press Release, 1984; RISM 18263; Grenada Foundation (New York); 2 pages (Box 11)
    - Cuban Statements on Grenada: Statement of the Party and the Revolutionary Government of Cuba Concerning the Events in Grenada, 1984; 4 pages (Box 11)
  - Grenada: Population, 1966 (Box 11)
    - Population Growth in Grenada in the Twentieth Century, 1966; RISM 17877; Harewood, Jack; p. 61-84. (Box 11)
      Population.; Grenada.
  - Grenada: Prisons (Box 11)
    - Report on the Prisons Department, 1950-1951; RISM 24441; Grenada. Prisons Department; 2 items; 1950, 1951; no content (Box 11)
      Grenada.; Prisons.
  - Grenada: Radio (Box 11)
    - List Showing Number of Radios Licensed in the Various Parishes of the Island During the Years, 1945-1953, RISM 24697; 3 pages (Box 11)
      Grenada.; Radio.
  - Grenada: Reading, Study and Teaching (Box 11)
    - Evaluation of Marryshow Readers, 1984; RISM 24708; University of the West Indies (Grenada). Extra-Mural Department; 11 pages (Box 11)
      Study and teaching.; Grenada.; Reading.
  - Grenada: Schools (Box 11)
    - Sunny Side School; Report Book, undated; RISM 24752; Sunny Side School (Grenada); unpaged. (Box 11)
      Grenada.; Schools.
    - St. Joseph's Convent School; Report Book, undated; RISM 24753; St. Joseph's Convent [School] (Grenada); unpaged. (Box 11)
      Schools.; Grenada.
    - St. George's Anglican Junior School; School Report, undated; RISM 24755; St. George's Anglican Junior School; 2 pages (Box 11)
    - The Anglican High School, 1916-1991, RISM 24765; 1 page (Box 11)
    - Short History of Westmoreland School, undated; RISM 24764; 5 pages (Box 11)
    - The Anglican High School: Tri-Weekly Progress Report, Form, undated; RISM 24767; Anglican High School (St. George's, Grenada); 1 page (Box 11)
    - Proposed Extension and Renovations to Anglican High School, 1986; RISM 24768; Walker, J. Douglas; 5 pages (Box 11)
    - St. Joseph's Roman Catholic School, 1990; RISM 24766; 2.0 (Box 11)
    - Presentation College, Grenada; Report for Parents and Guardians, undated; Presentation College (Grenada) (Box 11)
  - Grenada: Social Services (Box 11)
    - The Grenada Welfarer, 1947-1949; RISM 24712; 2 items; 7/47, 3/49; no content (Box 11)
      Grenada.; Social service.
    - Work Permits Issued to CARICOM Nationals to Work in Grenada, undated; RISM 24887; Grenada. Department of Labour; 3 pages (Box 11)
      Social service.; Grenada.
  - Grenada: Soils (Box 11)
    - The Cacao Soils of Grenada: Their Origins, Formation and Chief Characters, 1932; RISM 20767; Hardy, F.; 28 pages (Box 11)
      Grenada.; Soils.
  - Grenada: Statistics (Box 11)
    - Facts and Figures, 1980-1985; RISM 18489; Grenada. Statistical Department; 2 items; 1980, 1985; no content (Box 11)
      Grenada.; Statistics.
    - Statistical Pocket Digest, 1991, 1993; RISM 18490; Grenada. Central Statistics Office; 12 pages (Box 11)
    - Grenada Blue Book, 1866; Selected Pages, RISM 24693; 13 pages (Box 11)
      Statistics.; Grenada.
  - Grenada: Taxation (Box 11)
    - Taxation: Exchange of Information; Agreement Between the United States of America and Grenada, 1986; RISM 20769; United States. Department of State; 9 pages (Box 11)
      Grenada.; Taxation.
  - Grenada: Teachers, Training of (Box 11)
    - N.I.S.T.E.P. Teaching Manual, 1981; RISM 24751; Broomes, Desmond; 19 pages (Box 11)
      Teachers; Grenada.
    - Grenada Teachers' College: Inservice Education, 1986-1987, RISM 24772; Grenada Teachers' College; 4 pages (Box 11)
      Grenada.; Teachers
    - Department of Teacher Education: Inservice 1990, Semester I, RISM 24773; Grenada. Dept. of Teacher Education; 2 pages (Box 11)
  - Grenada: Tourism (Box 11)
    - Report on the Grenada Tourist Board for the Year 1965, 1967; RISM 20770; Grenada. Ministry of Agriculture, Tourism, Forestry, and Fisheries; 11 pages (Box 11)
      Grenada.; Tourism.
    - Address to the Nation; Performance of the Tourism Sector - First Six Months of 1985, RISM 24756; Brizan, George I.; 8 pages (Box 11)
    - Grenada: A Tourist Paradise?, 1991; 8 pages (Box 11)
      Tourism.; Grenada.
  - Grenada: Trade Unions (Box 11)
    - List of Trade Unions, 1952; RISM 24714; Grenada. Department of Labour; 5 pages (Box 11)
      Labor unions; Grenada.
  - Grenada: Trials (Box 11)
    - Chester Humphrey Freed! History Created in Court, 1986; RISM 23098; 3 pages (Box 11)
      Trials.; Grenada.
  - Grenada: Vocational Education (Box 11)
    - The Newlo Story: A Newlo 'Tour Guide' Programme, 1990; RISM 24769; Loe-Sack-Sioe, Reina; 14 pages (Box 11)
    - NEWLO Vocational Training Centre for Youth, undated; RISM 24770; Loe-Sack-Sioe, Reina; 2 pages (Box 11)
    - Grenada Technical and Vocational Institute; Welding, undated; RISM 24774; Julien, Ashley; 3 pages (Box 11)
- Guadeloupe, undated, 1945-2000 (Box 11)
  Guadeloupe.
  - Guadeloupe: Adolescence (Box 11)
    Guadeloupe.; Adolescence -- Guadeloupe.
    - Attitudes and Problems of Adolescents in Guadeloupe. Benoit, Guy p. 62-63., 1962 (Box 11)
      Adolescence -- Guadeloupe.
  - Guadeloupe: Agriculture, 1990 (Box 11)
    Agriculture |z Guadeloupe.
    - L'Agriculture Guadeloupeenne en Chiffres France. Direction departementale de l'agriculture (Guadeloupe). 24.0 pages ill., tables, 1990 (Box 11)
  - Guadeloupe: Autonomy (Box 11)
    - La "Question du Statut": Notre Propoosition Groupe revolution socialiste. 12.0 pages, 1991 (Box 11)
      Guadeloupe.; Autonomy.
  - Guadeloupe: Carib Indians (Box 11)
    - Reflexions sur la Calebasse de R. Fortune Sthl, H. 7.0 pages, 1949 (Box 11)
      Guadeloupe.; Carib Indians |z Guadeloupe.; Carib Indians.
  - Guadeloupe: Cooperative Societies (Box 11)
    - L'Affaire Zevallos: Communication Presentee lors de la XIIIe Conference de l'Association des Historiens de la Caraibe Buffon, Alain 10.0 pages, 1981 (Box 11)
      Cooperative societies |z Guadeloupe.
  - Guadeloupe: Creole Dialects, French (Box 11)
    - The Problematic of Creole Lexicography Schnepel, Ellen M. p. 237-246, 1991 (Box 11)
      Creole dialects, French |z Guadeloupe.
  - Guadeloupe: Description and Travel (Box 11)
    - The Isles of Guadeloupe Gottmann, Jean p. 182-203., 1945 (Box 11)
      Guadeloupe |x Description and travel.
    - Le Plan des Villes de la Guadeloupe, 1988-89 Lequime, Erik 50.0 pages, 1988-1989 (Box 11)
    - Traditions and Culture Chartrol, Edouard 4.0 pages, undated (Box 11)
    - Background Notes: Guadeloupe Unitee States Dept. of State. 4.0 pages, 1969 (Box 11)
    - La Municipalite vous Souhaite la Beinvenue a Pointe-A-Pitre;La Guadeloupe. Guadeloupe Foire-Exposition (1960:Pointe-a-Pitre). 40.0 pages map (Box 11)
    - Guadeloupe, French Caribbean Office departemental du tourisme de la Guadeloupe 6.0 pages, undated (Box 11)
    - Guadeloupe; Overseas Department of France 7.0 pages, 2000 (Box 11)
  - Guadeloupe: East Indians (Box 11)
    - Le Mouvement Creole et sa Signification pour l'Intergration Sociale et Politique des Indiens en Guadeloupe Schnepel, Ellen M p. 43-63., 1989 (Box 11)
      East Indians |z Guadeloupe.
    - Assimilation of East Indians on a French West Indian Island Gooseen, Jean G. 22.0 pages, 1974 (Box 11)
    - Les Indiens de la Guadeloupe Lasserre, GUy p. 86-89, c. 1976 (Box 11)
  - Guadeloupe: Economic Conditions (Box 11)
    - Avantages Financiers et Fiscaux Reserves aux Investissements Industries Industries et Hoteliers Guadeloupe. Secretariat general pour les affaires economiques. 33.0 pages, 1966 (Box 11)
      Guadeloupe |x Economic conditions.
  - Guadeloupe: Education (Box 11)
    - Guadeloupe Education: Special Report, No. 20 Centre departemental de documentation pedagogique (Guadeloupe). 27.0 pages, 1988 (Box 11)
      Education |z Guadeloupe.
    - Hommage a un Amimateur de la Jeuness Guadeloupeenne Micaux, Maurice 47.0 pages, 1965 (Box 11)
  - Guadeloupe: Family (Box 11)
    - Child Sharing and Foster Parenthood in the French West Indies. Goossen, Jean G. 21.0 pages, 1971 (Box 11)
      Family |z Guadeloupe.
  - Guadeloupe: Festivals (Box 11)
    - Guadeloupe Market Women and their Festivities Goosen, Jean G. 11.0 pages, 1973 (Box 11)
      Festivals |z Guadeloupe.
  - Guadeloupe: Folklore (Box 11)
    - Folklore de la Guadeloupe: La Veillee Mortuaire & "Le Cric-Crac" unpaged, undated (Box 11)
      Folklore |z Guadeloupe.
    - "Le Cric Crac,": Jeux de Mots et Devinettes de Veillee Mourtuaire Recueillis a Saint-Claude par Roger Fortune lors de la Veillee Mortuiar de Madame Melteor unpaged, 1951 (Box 11)
  - Guadeloupe: History (Box 11)
    - Ambiguous Revolution in the Caribbean: The White Jacobins, 1789-1800 Protin-Dumon, Anne 18.0 pages, 1984 (Box 11)
      Guadeloupe |x History.
    - Marceline Desbordes a la Guadeloupe Bourgeois, Gaston 29.0 pages, 1948 (Box 11)
    - Ville de Pointe-A-Pitre: Bicentenaire de sa Creation Pointe-a-Pitre (Guadeloupe). 45.0 pages, 1965-1966 (Box 11)
  - Guadeloupe: Investments (Box 11)
    - Guadeloupe Investment Incentives. 30.0 cm, ca. 1986 (Box 11)
      Investments |z Guadeloupe.
  - Guadeloupe: Land Use (Box 11)
    - Land Use in Guadeloupe Augelli, John P. 3.0 pages pg. 436-438 (Box 11)
      Guadeloupe.; Land use.
  - Guadeloupe: Marriage (Box 11)
    - Le Choix du Conjoint chex les Blancs-Matignons de la Guadeloupe: Criteres Economiques et Criteres Raciaux Chartrand, Francine, 1965 (Box 11)
      Marriage |z Guadeloupe.
  - Guadeloupe: Medical Care (Box 11)
    - Medecine et Psychiatrie Rurale en Guadeloupe Pineau, A., (Andre) p. 413-416, 1960 (Box 11)
      Medical care |z Guadeloupe.
  - Guadeloupe: National Parks and Reserves (Box 11)
    - Parc Naturel de Guadeloupe; French West Indies Guadeloupe. Office national des forets. 6.0 pages, undated (Box 11)
      Guadeloupe.; National parks and reserves.
  - Guadeloupe: Population (Box 11)
    - Guadeloupe: Evolutions Demographiques 1975-1982-1990 Institut national de la statstique et des etudes economiques (France). Direction interregionale Antilles-Guyane. 16.0 pages, ca. 1992 (Box 11)
      Guadeloupe |x Population.
  - Guadeloupe: Social Life and Customs (Box 11)
    - Recueil de Scenes Vecues a la Guadeloupe: Moeurs Expressions Creoles, Etc. Buneul, Francois 24.0 pages, ca. 1962 (Box 11)
      Guadeloupe.; Manners and customs
  - Guadeloupe: Spices (Box 11)
    - Le Commerce de l'Epicerie a Travers les Ages; Conference Donnee a la Section Guadeloupeenne du Centre des Jeunes Patrons William, Germain 39.0 pages, 1965 (Box 11)
      Spices |z Guadeloupe.
  - Guadeloupe: Sports (Box 11)
    - La Vie du Cygne Noir: De Sa Fondation a ce Jour Pentier, M. Fernand 27.0 pages, ca. 1964 (Box 11)
      Sports |z Guadeloupe.
  - Guadeloupe: Statistics (Box 11)
    - La Guadeloupe en Quelques Chiffres Institut National de la Statstique et des Etudes Economiques (France). Service departemental de la Guadeloupe. 2.0 items, 1980-1989 (Box 11)
      Guadeloupe |v Statistics.
  - Guadeloupe: Taxation (Box 11)
    - The Tax and Customs Systems Applicable in Guadeloupe 9.0 pages, undated (Box 11)
      Taxation |z Guadeloupe.
  - Guadeloupe: Tourist Trade (Box 11)
    - Impact Economique du Tourisme Guadeloupe. 6.0 pages, 1983 (Box 11)
      Tourism |z Guadeloupe.
  - Guadeloupe: Volcanoes (Box 11)
    Volcanoes |z Guadeloupe.
- Haiti (Box 12)
  - Haiti: Adult Education (Box 12)
    - Je m'Instruis en Lisant et en Observant, undated; RISM 16680; Haiti. Département de l'éducation nationale. Section de l'éducation des adultes; 16 pages (Box 12)
      Adult education.; Haiti
    - Vade Mecum: A l'Usage des Moniteurs des Centre de l'Education des Adultes, 1953; RISM 20913; Haiti. Département de l'éducation nationale. Section de l'éducation des adultes; 6 pages (Box 12)
  - Haiti: Agricultural Assistance, America (Box 12)
    - Integrated Agricultural Development; Agreement Between the United States of America and Haiti, 1976; RISM 16695; United States. Department of State; 9 pages (Box 12)
      Agricultural assistance, American.; Haiti
  - Haiti: Agricultural Laborers (Box 12)
    - Affiliations Through Work in Marbial, Haiti, 1952; RISM 24154; Métraux, Rhoda, 1914-2003; 22 pages; p. 1-22. (Box 12)
      Agricultural laborers.; Haiti
  - Haiti: Agriculture (Box 12)
    - Croyances Populaires et Systemes Agricoles Traditionnels en Haiti, 1980; RISM 24213; Pillot, Didier; p. 17-28. (Box 12)
      Agriculture.; Haiti
    - Land Use and Agriculture in the Peligre Basin, 1984; RISM 16720; Kulibaba, Nicholas P.; 16 pages (Box 12)
  - Haiti: Anthropology, Physical (Box 12)
    - Anthropologie Physique de la Population de l'Ile de la Tortue (Haiti) Contribution a l'Etude de l'Origine des Noirs des Antilles Francaises, 1962; RISM 20915; Benoist, Jean, 1929-; p. 315-335. (Box 12)
      Anthropology, Physical.; Haiti
  - Haiti: Armed Forces (Box 12)
    - On Controlling the Colonels, 1970; RISM 20928; Nicholls, David, 1936-; 5 pages (Box 12)
      Armed Forces.; Haiti
  - Haiti: Art (Box 12)
    - Artists of the Western Hemisphere: Art of Haiti and Jamaica, Loan Exhibition, 1968; RISM 16820; Center for Inter-American Relations; unpaged. (Box 12)
      Art.; Haiti
  - Haiti: Bibliography (Box 12)
    - Bibliography of Haitian Studies, Extract; 1957-1968, undated; RISM 20929; Lubin, Maurice Alcibiade, 1917-; 42 pages (Box 12)
      Bibliography.; Haiti
    - Bibliographie d'Haiti, 1994, 1995; RISM 20930; Laroche, Maximilien; 21 pages (Box 12)
    - Materials in the National Archives Relating to Haiti, 1949; RISM 20931; Pomrenze, Seymour J.; 13 pages (Box 12)
    - A Select Bibliography on Haiti, 1969; RISM 20932; Bellegarde-Smith, Patrick; 14 pages (Box 12)
    - A Selective Social Science Bibliography of the Republic of Haiti, 1963; RISM 20933; Mintz, Sidney W. (Sidney Wilfred), 1922-2015; p. 405-417. (Box 12)
      Haiti; Bibliography.
  - Haiti: Birth Control (Box 12)
    - Use of Family Planning in Haiti: A Comparison of Survey Data and Service Statistics, undated; RISM 17005; Allman, James, 1943-; 15 pages (Box 12)
      Haiti; Birth control.
    - Culture, Natality, and Family Planning, 1981; RISM 20916; Marshall, John F.; p. 59-79. (Box 12)
  - Haiti: Birth Customs (Box 12)
    - La Naissance a Kenscoff, Haiti, 1959; RISM 23006; Comhaire-Sylvain, Suzanne; p. 555-572. (Box 12)
      Haiti; Birth customs.
    - Women in Perdition: Ritual Fertility Control in Haiti, 1976; Murray, Gerald F. (Box 12)
  - Haiti: Breast Feeding (Box 12)
    - Current Breast-Feeding and Weaning Practices in Haiti, 1980; RISM 17180; Graitcer, Philip L.; 12 pages (Box 12)
      Haiti; Breastfeeding.
  - Haiti: Carnival (Box 12)
    - Le Carnaval dans nos Moeurs, 1993; RISM 25153; Haiti. Bureau national d'ethnologie; p. 82-105. (Box 12)
      Haiti; Carnival.
  - Haiti: Children (Box 12)
    - Peasant Children's Games in Northern Haiti, 1954; RISM 17748; Simpson, George Eaton, 1904-1998; p. 65-73 (Box 12)
      Haiti; Children.
  - Haiti: Civil Rights (Box 12)
    - Human Rights in Haiti: One Year Under General Prosper Avril, 1989; RISM 17610; Americas Watch Committee (U.S.); 15 pages (Box 12)
      Civil rights.; Haiti
    - Extraits de Documents Officels sur la Situation des Droits de l'Homme en Haiti, 1969; RISM 17611; Inter-American Commission on Human Rights; 6 pages (Box 12)
    - A Human Rights Scandal: Policy and Practice in the USA, 1992; RISM 20917; Martin, Ian; 1 page (Box 12)
    - Excerpts from the Haitian Human Rights Platform's Memorandum to the Organization of American States (OAS) Mission Visiting Haiti, 1992; RISM 20918; Haiti Communications Project; 2 pages (Box 12)
    - Human Rights Violations in Haiti, 1991; RISM 20919; Washington Office on Haiti; 3 pages (Box 12)
    - Recent Violations of Human Rights in Haiti: An Update of the June 1980 Report of the Lawyers Committee for International Human Rights Submitted to the United Nations Ecosoc Resolution 1503 (XLVIII), 1981; RISM 20920; Lawyers Committee for International Human Rights; 20 pages (Box 12)
    - Coalition for Civilian Observers in Haiti, 1992; RISM 23162; 2 pages (Box 12)
  - Haiti: Coffee (Box 12)
    - More Coffee - More Income for Haiti's Small Farmer, 1976; RISM 17668; Metelsky, John; p. 5-12 (Box 12)
      Coffee.; Haiti
  - Haiti: Commerce (Box 12)
    - Doing Business with Haiti, 1985; RISM 20950; United States. Office of International Trade; 15 pages (Box 12)
      Haiti; Commerce.
    - Haiti's Agriculture and Trade, ca. 1969; RISM 20951; Buck, Wilbur F. (Wilbur Francis), 1907-; 19 pages (Box 12)
    - Foreign Trade Regulations of Haiti, 1970; RISM 18969; Haidar, Walter; 5 pages (Box 12)
  - Haiti: Constitution (Box 12)
    - Constitution of Haiti, 1964, 1968; RISM 20936; Organization of American States. General Secretariat; 33 pages (Box 12)
      Haiti; Constitutions.
    - Constitution of Haiti, 1964 (as Amended, 1971), 1974; RISM 20935; Organization of American States. General Secretariat; 34 pages (Box 12)
    - Constitution et Statuts Declaration de Principes Communique de Presse, 1981; RISM 20934; Haiti. Constitution; unpaged. (Box 12)
  - Haiti: Creole Dialects (Box 12)
    - Nasalization in Creole French, 1970; RISM 17777; Valdman, Albert; p. 967-971. (Box 12)
      Haiti; Creole dialects.
    - The Dialect Differences of Haitian Creole, ca. 1971; RISM 17782; Klein, Wilma; 13 pages (Box 12)
    - Devenir du Creole Haitian, 1952; RISM 17783; Hyppolite, Michelson Paul; 21 pages (Box 12)
      Creole dialects.; Haiti
    - Kreol; 1, 2, and 3, 1959-1960; RISM 17784; Haiti. Division du développement rural; 3 items; nos. 1, 2, 3; no content (Box 12)
    - The Functional Distribution of Creole and French in Haiti, 1959; RISM 17785; Stewart, William A.; p. 149-159. (Box 12)
    - Be in Samana English, 1988; RISM 20921; Debose, Charles E., 1939-; 18 pages (Box 12)
    - Ann Konte, Ann Kalkule, 1953; RISM 23492; Haiti. Département de l'éducation nationale. Section de l'éducation des adultes; 30 pages (Box 12)
    - M-Ap Apprann Li, 1953; RISM 23493; Haiti. Département de l'éducation nationale. Section de l'éducation des adultes; 24 pages (Box 12)
    - French and Creole Patois in Haiti, 1954; RISM 24005; Efron, Edith, 1922-; p. 199-213 (Box 12)
  - Haiti: Culture (Box 12)
    - HSA Newsletter; Newsletter of the Haitian Studies Association, 2002-2002; Haitian Studies Association; 2 items (Box 12)
      Culture.; Haiti
  - Haiti: Dancing (Box 12)
    - Le Tambour et la Danse Religieuse dans la Liturgie Chretienne en Haiti, 1972; RISM 17892; Laguerre, Michel S.; p. 587-603 (Box 12)
      Haiti; Dance.
  - Haiti: Description and Travel (Box 12)
    - Focus: Haiti, 1967; RISM 20947; Gildea, Ray Y.; 6 pages (Box 12)
      Haiti
    - Haiti: West Africa in the West Indies, 1961; RISM 20946; Scofield, John; p. 226-259. (Box 12)
    - Promenade Port-au-Prince, 1939; RISM 20945; Comhaire-Sylvain, Jean; p. 356-368. (Box 12)
    - Haiti: Against All Odds, 1987; RISM 20937; Cobb, Charles E.; p. 645-670. (Box 12)
    - Haiti: Its Pulse Is Its People, undated; RISM 20939; Hunter, David; p. 11-14. (Box 12)
    - Introduction to Haiti, 1959; RISM 20938; Pan American Union; 2 pages (Box 12)
    - Background Notes: Haiti, 1967-1998; RISM 20940; United States. Bureau of Inter-American Affairs; 6 items; 10/67, 4/77, 2/81, 4/87, 11/94, 3/98; no content (Box 12)
    - Haiti, 2000; RISM 26339; 8 pages; 8.0 (Box 12)
    - Haiti Hotel Guide, undated (Box 12)
    - Welcome to Haiti International Country Club: General Information, undated; 14 pages (Box 12)
  - Haiti: Diseases (Box 12)
    - Yellow Fever in the 1790s: The British Army in Occupied Saint Domingue, 1979; RISM 17867; Geggus, David Patrick; p. 38-58. (Box 12)
      Haiti; Diseases.
  - Haiti: Drug Trade (Box 12)
    - Narcotic Drugs: Interdiction of Trafficking; Agreement Between the United States of America and Haiti, 1981; RISM 20926; United States. Department of State; 7 pages (Box 12)
      Haiti; Drug traffic.
  - Haiti: Economic Conditions (Box 12)
    - Mobilizing Resources for Development: A Retrospect on President Aristide's Economic Strategy for Haiti and His Administration Record with Aid Donors, 1992; RISM 20952; Center for International Policy (Washington, D.C.); 8 pages (Box 12)
      Economic conditions.; Haiti
    - Economic Dependence: U.S. Solutions to Haiti's Economic Problems, 1978; RISM 20953; R‌emy, Anselme; 12 pages (Box 12)
    - Haiti, Starting the Climb: 'Land of Mountains' Faces Many Barriers in Development, 1977; RISM 20954; Chernush, Kay; 7 pages (Box 12)
    - Foreign Economic Trends and Their Implications for the United States: Haiti, 1977-1989; RISM 20955; United States. Office of International Trade; 2 items; 11/77, 5/89; no content (Box 12)
    - A Businessman's Guide to Haiti, 1978; RISM 20957; Haiti. Secrétairerie d'État du commerce et de l'industrie; 22 pages (Box 12)
    - Guide de l'Homme d'Affaires en Haiti, 1978; RISM 20958; Haiti. Secrétairerie d'État du commerce et de l'industrie; 22 pages (Box 12)
    - Haiti: Les Moyens de sa Liberation Economique, 1986; RISM 20959; Dominique, Hilaire; 31 pages (Box 12)
    - Investing in Haiti, 1986; RISM 20960; Caribbean/Central American Action (Organization); 18 pages (Box 12)
    - A Propos de la Question d'Unite Monetaire en Haiti, 1955; RISM 20961; Estève, Édouard; 32 pages (Box 12)
      Haiti; Economic conditions.
    - Basic Data on the Economy of Haiti, 1970; RISM 18970; Haidar, Walter; 8 pages (Box 12)
    - Holiness and the Literary Mind, undated; RISM 24970; Elmen, Paul; p. 232-233. (Box 12)
    - Discurso en los Actos de Graduacion de la Universidad Interamericana en san German, 1989; RISM 25276; Latortue, Gérard R.; 14 pages (Box 12)
    - The Employment of Capital by Market Women in Haiti, ca. 1960; Mintz, Sidney W. (Sidney Wilfred), 1922-2015 (Box 12)
  - Haiti: Education (Box 12)
    - Schooling in Haiti, 1979; RISM 11144; Laguerre, Michel S.; 9.0 (Box 12)
      Haiti; Education.
  - Haiti: Emigration and Immigration (Box 12)
    - The Haitians Versus the United States: The Courts as Last Resort, 1983; RISM 20962; Flink-Zucker, Naomi; p. 151-162. (Box 12)
      Haiti; Emigration and immigration.
    - Cloud of Despair Still Hangs Over Haitians, 1984; RISM 20963; Slevin, Peter; 3 pages (Box 12)
    - The Haitianization of Guyana Deepens, 1985; RISM 20964; Kwayana, Eusi; 2 pages (Box 12)
    - The Immigration War: Foreign Policy vs. Human Policy, 1982; RISM 20965; 5 pages (Box 12)
    - Cuban-Haitian Entrants, 1980; RISM 20966; United States. Department of State. Bureau of Public Affairs; 2 pages (Box 12)
    - Haitian Asylum Cases, 1980; RISM 20967; United States. Department of State. Bureau of Public Affairs; 2 pages (Box 12)
    - Cuban-Haitian Arrivals in the U.S., 1980; RISM 20968; Palmieri, Victor H.; 2 pages (Box 12)
    - Haitian Migration to the U.S., 1980; RISM 20969; Bushnell, John A.; 6 pages (Box 12)
    - Haitian Migration: 30 Years Assessed, 1982; RISM 20970; Allman, James, 1943-; p. 7-12. (Box 12)
    - Haiti: More U.S. Aid Means More Refugees, 1983; RISM 20971; Kenkelen, Bill; 2 pages (Box 12)
    - Haitian Refugees: (Haiti's) Missing Persons, 1979; RISM 20972; Bogre, Michelle; p. 9-11. (Box 12)
      Emigration and immigration.; Haiti
    - The Haitian Case: Louis vs. Nelson, 1982; RISM 23153; Kurzban, Ira J.; p. 5-7. (Box 12)
    - Haitian Boat People: Causes and Methods of Migration, 1997; RISM 20312; 8 pages (Box 12)
    - Haitian Americans, undated; Laguerre, Michel S. (Box 12)
  - Haiti: Family (Box 12)
    - Haitian Attitudes Toward Family Size, 1962; RISM 18107; Stycos, J. Mayone; 18 pages (Box 12)
      Family.; Haiti